Guide to the Bert Morgan Photographic Negatives circa 1932-1963, 1981 (bulk, 1960-1961) PR 367
New-York Historical Society
- The Bourbon Ball Hotel Plaza [70 negatives in 49 sleeves], 1961 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Platt, Harry (Tiffany executive)
  Rainville, Mrs. Gustave
  Reynolds, John J. Sr.
  Rovensky, John E.
  Rutherfurd, Jay (with ex-wife, Mrs. Anthony Hunter)
  Scheftel, Herbert and Mrs.
  Schmidlapp, Mrs. Horace
  Smaltz, Mrs. John C.
  Statter, Humphrey
  Tankoos, Joseph
  Thibault, Conrad and Mrs.
  Trout, Thaddeus
  Vanderstraeten, Mrs. Roger
  Westerman, Samuel L. (president, T. W. Samuels Distillery)
  Whitney, Cornelius V. and Mrs.
- National Horse Show Ball, Hotel Astor, N.Y. [30 negatives in 22 sleeves], 1961 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Alexandre, Frederick F.
  Ballantine, Mary E.
  Bland, James
  Briggs, Peter
  Briggs, Sharon
  Clark, Samuel Adams
  Cole, Brigadier-General John T. and Mrs.
  Duke, St. George "Pony"
  Gutierrez, Señora Dono Eugenia De
  Henneck, Carol
  Jones, Mrs. Charles (former Hope Haskell)
  Joy, James
  O'Donnell, Dale and Mrs.
  O'Donohoe, Lt. Eamon
  Raeder, Robert and Mrs.
  Ryan, Mrs. Priscilla St. George
  Shepard, Judith
  Soames, Sarah
  Stockard, Leslie (daughter of Mrs. Lester N. Stockard)
  Stockman, Mrs. Henry C.
  Sturges, A. Mary
  Terrell, Howard Jr.
  Tompkins, Boylston A. and Mrs.
  Tuckerman, Major-General Alfred G. and Mrs.
  Van Lennepp, Frederick and Mrs. (former Frances Dodge)
  Van Nini, Henry and Mrs.
- The Twist Party at The Four Seasons [for] Plymouth Florida Girls Town [53 negatives in 33 sleeves], 1961 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  A dinner-dance held at the Four Seasons to benefit Girls Town in Mount Plymouth, Florida, a proposed refuge for homeless girls.
  Adams, Alice
  Baez, Yolanda
  Brine, Paul Jr.
  Butler, Robin
  Cappella, Jacques and Mrs.
  Cash, Annette
  Cassini, Oleg
  Chalk, O. Roy and Mrs. (parents of Mrs. Henry Hubsham)
  Coakley, Wm. Duncan and Mrs.
  Crossman, Cmdr. Harold and Mrs. (Florence Lustig, noted designer)
  Davis, Lewis C.
  Dehi, Raymonde
  Dodge, Mrs. Horace E.
  Fontayne (famous designer)
  Gregory, John
  Greenlief, Crawford
  Hubsham, Henry and Mrs.
  Javits, Eric M. and Mrs.
  Johnson, Raymond and Mrs.
  Kins, Gloria
  Kleinbaum, Mrs. Alfred
  Lanvin, Bernard
  Lauder, Joseph and Mrs. (Estee Lauder)
  Lydon, Thomas and Mrs.
  Martino, H. E. Gaetano (head of Italian Delegation, United Nations)
  McGinty, Thomas J. and Mrs.
  Parks, Bernice
  Pfeiffer, Ambassador William and Mrs.
  Rahm, Mrs. William de
  Revson, Charles
  Robinson, Mrs. Sinclair
  Rubirosa, Porfirio and Mrs.
  St. George, Maria
  Sisman, Mrs. Florence
  Stein, Susan
  Taylor, Henry J. (Ambassador to Switzerland from U.S.)
  Thorne, Mrs. Henry S.
  Weissman, Frederick P. and Mrs.
- Bal Polonaise, Sheraton-East, N.Y. [41 negatives in 30 sleeves], 1961 November 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Benefit for Polish Mutual Assistance, an organization that aided Polish refugees of World War II and the years following.
  Alemany, Carlos
  Bernham, Joseph and Mrs.
  Berns, Charles A. and Mrs. (of "21")
  Bourisk, Robert
  Colby, Anita
  Coppet, Mrs. Andre de
  Ehret, George
  Escobar, Marisol
  Estevez, Luis and Mrs.
  Gilbert, Mrs. Edward
  Kiepura, Jan and Mrs.
  Leitao, Pedro
  Lipton, Michael and Mrs.
  Lowell, Mrs. James Russell
  Morgan, Urban
  Neff, Joseph and Mrs.
  Paolozzi, Christina
  Phillips, Lynn and Mrs.
  Punnet, Roy
  Rubinstein, Mrs. Arthur (chairman of Bal Polonaise)
  Stewart, Serena (daughter of Mrs. Wm. Rhinelander Stewart)
  Straus, Mrs. Ralph I. (chairman of Dinner Committee)
  Thurn und Taxis, Princess Almerie
  Tillis, Mr. James
  Vanden-Heuvel, William and Mrs.
  Windisch-Graetz, Princess
  Wright, Frank
  Young, Mrs. Patricia (niece of Mrs. E. N. Graham, "Elizabeth Arden")
- P.A.L. [Police Athletic League] Ball [20 negatives in 13 sleeves], 1961 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Annual benefit for the Police Athletic League of New York City, a non-profit youth development agency, held in the ballroom of the Sheraton-East Hotel.
  Benedict, Vicki
  Bogert, Beverly
  Brooks, Harry A.
  Brukenfeld, Jane
  Butler, Mrs. Robin
  Chapman, Richard D.
  Davie, Mrs. T. Bedford (former Diana Wing)
  Granger, Mrs. Wm. G.
  Holzer, Leonard
  McGrath, Mrs. Gordon R.
  Phipps, Nonie
  Rayner, Wm. G. and Mrs.
  Reeves, Joan (daughter of Mrs. T. W. Blake)
  Santangelo, Michael
  Stewart, Serena
- April in Paris Ball, Hotel Americana [1 EMPTY envelope], 1962 October 26 (Box 3, Envelope back of box)
  The eleventh "April in Paris" ball, held at the Hotel Americana, and benefiting the French Hospital, the National Racing Museum of Saratoga, New York, and French and American charities.
  Breer, Mrs. Wall
  Cassini, Igor and Mrs.
  Home, Mrs. Douglas
  Hood, Clifford F. and Mrs.
  Miniato, Duke and Duchess Pini de san
  Rotz, John L. and Mrs.
- April in Paris Ball [4 negatives in 4 sleeves], 1963 October 25 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  The twelfth "April in Paris" ball, held at the Hotel Americana, with the theme "La Femme" (woman), benefiting the American French Foundation.
  Atlas, Mrs. Frank
  Delaney, Robert
  Lehman, Mrs. Orin
  Morell, Leo
  Platzer, Mrs. Edith
  Rutherfurd, John M. L. and Mrs.
  St. Lewis, Roy and Mrs.
  Smith, Ethel
  Tankoos, S. Joseph Jr.
  White, Robert W. and Mrs.
  Willfort, Johannes G. (Consul General of Austria)
- Bourbon Ball, Hotel Plaza, N.Y. [2 negatives with 1 print in 2 sleeves], 1963 October 31 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Benefit for the Soldiers', Sailors', Marines', Coast Guard and Airmen's Club (283 Lexington Avenue, Manhattan). The ball's theme: Christmas on Halloween.
  Benjamin, Mrs. De Bruniere
  Kiser, Mrs. John W. [photo taken for]
- Belmont Ball, Roseland Ballroom, N.Y. [21 color negatives in 1 envelope], 1981 June 5 (Box 3, Envelope back of box)
  These negatives are in color.
  Augustus, Ms. Peggy
  Baker, Bob and Mrs.
  Burns, Daniel
  Firestone, Mrs. Myrna
  Goldstein, Herbert and Mrs.
  Kelly, Thomas J. and Mrs.
  Kumble, Steven and Mrs.
  McGuire, Edward
  Phipps, Ogden M. and Mrs.
  Ritzenberg, Milton
  Roberts, Ms. Grace
  Roosevelt, Franklin D. Jr. and Mrs.
  Ruegg, Jack and Mrs.
  Tuttle, Wylie F. L. and Mrs.
- Belmont Ball [1 negative in 1 sleeve], undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Deegan, Mrs. Thomas J. Jr.
  Gimbel, Bernard
- Blue Grass Ball, Hotel Plaza, N.Y. [40 negatives in 27 sleeves], undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Anderson, Roy and Mrs.
  Armstrong, Robert and Mrs.
  Austin, Edward B. and Mrs.
  Braverman, Marvin
  Carmichael, Robert H. and Mrs.
  Deegan, Thomas J. and Mrs.
  Fehlhaber, Fred and Mrs.
  Fischer-Banzon, Hans
  Graff, G. Bertram and Mrs.
  Hunter, Francis T. and Mrs.
  Jaffe, Mrs. Wm. B.
  Johnson, Sanford and Mrs.
  Macpherson, Arthur and Mrs.
  Murray, Allan
  Rabe, William G. and Mrs.
  Schmid, Robert and Mrs.
  Stemmler, Theodore W. and Mrs.
  Stuart, James B. and Mrs.
  Thibault, Conrad
  Trunz, Mrs. Charles M.
  Whitney, Mrs. Eleanor Searle
  Woodward, Mrs. Wm. Jr.
- Hotel Americana [28 negatives in 23 sleeves], undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  These images possibly relate to the "April in Paris" balls, also held at the Hotel Americana. See box 3, folder 5, and the empty envelope in the back of box 3.
  Bryce, Mrs. John F. C.
  Chickering, Don and Mrs.
  Crossman, Mrs. Harold (Florence Lustig)
  Donahue, Mrs. Woolworth
  Dubonnet, Andre
  Eristavi, Princess Diane
  Gardiner, Robert and Mrs.
  Graf, Mrs. Bruno K.
  Griffis, Stanton
  Hanes, John W.
  Hunt, Mrs. Elise
  Legendre, Bokara
  McGivern, Mrs. Owen
  McLean, Mrs. John R.
  McMahon, Frank and Mrs.
  Miniatio, Duke Pini de san
  Mori, Mrs. Eugene
  Nelson, Mrs. Herbert
  Phillipe, Claudius
  Rainville, Mrs. Gustave H.
  Reed, Mrs. Stass (Martha Cuneo)
  Sanford, Stephen and Mrs.
  Shirley, Walter T. Sr. and Mrs.
  Von Ferstenberg, Betsy
  Windisch-Graetz, Princess Veriand (former Caroline Knott)
- [individuals] [5 negatives in 5 sleeves], undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Budd, Mrs. Kenneth P.
  Gray, Beatrice (daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Henry G. Gray)
  Milbank, Margaret (daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Jeremiah Milbank)
  Raymond, Carolyn (daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Raymond)
  Wilson, Mrs. Harry
- SS Queen of Bermuda [9 negatives in 5 sleeves], undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  British cruise ship operated by the Furness Bermuda Line, 1933-1966.
  Alexander, Henry Clay and Mrs. (former Janet Hutchinson)
  Grafton, William D. and Mrs.
  Kingsbury, Frederick Hutchinson and Mrs. (former Charlotte Meyer)
  Lee, Walter John and Mrs.
  Robinson, James D. Jr. and Mrs.
- [GLASS] Fashion Show at Hotel Carlisle [Hotel Carlyle] [2 plates], circa 1932-1934 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  Mary B. Mixsell (daughter of Harold Ruckman Mixsell)
  [Mary B. Mixsell debuted on 22 September 1932 and married Carlisle Norwood 4th on 2 October 1934.]
- [GLASS] National Horse Show [2 plates], 1934 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  Kneeland, John (on Mickey Mouse)
  St. George, Priscilla
- [GLASS] 71st Regiment, Park Ave N.Y. [1 plate], 1934 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Hutton, J. L. (son of John L. Hutton)
  Stetson, William (son of Rufus C. Stetson)
  Topping, John (son of Mr. and Mrs. Henry J. Topping)
  Wood, Howard O. 3rd (son of Mr. and Mrs. Howard Ogden Wood Jr.)
- [GLASS] St. Bartholomew's Church, New York, N.Y. [1 plate], [1934 January 5] (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Wedding of Mr. and Mrs. Potter Cox. (Bride former Betty Buckner, daughter of Emory R. Buckner; groom son of Mrs. William Stuart Forbes.)
- [GLASS] St. Bartholomew's Church, New York, N.Y. [1 plate], [1934 April 12] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Mrs. Edward K. Jenkins [bride] (former Betty Willets).
- [GLASS] Fifth Ave. Presbyterian Church [4 plates], [1934 November 18] (Box 4, Folder 8-11)
  Wedding of Mr. and Mrs. Tennyson Newsom (bride former Josephine Paull).
- [GLASS] At Flower Show [1 plate], undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Payne, Mrs. Daniel
- [GLASS] On Park Avenue [6 plates], undated (Box 4, Folder 13-18)
  Bruen, Constance L. J. F.
  Post, Mrs. Langdon W.
  Robbins, Frances E. (daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Harry Pelham Robbins)
  Sperry, Marjorie (daughter of Mrs. E. I. Goodrich)
  Sterling, Mrs. Duncan
  Sterling, Edythe
  Wilson, Gretchen